Guide to the Field family papers, 1851-1881.
Field family papers, 1851-1881.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Field family papers, 1851-1881.
1547
Field family.
.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, a diary, photographs, other papers, and assorted memorabilia.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence of William R. Field, Pittstown, New York, and Mary Hyde (Field) of New York; diary of Mary Hyde; letter from James A. Garfield, Ohio, to Mary Maxon Hyde Field, acknowledging her recent letter and recalling his graduation from Williams College; autographed photograph of Garfield (1880); F.W. Field's notes on his family's acquaintance with President Garfield and on the Hyde and Field genealogies; daguerreotype (ca. 1860) of Mrs. William Field holding her infant daughter, Addie Hyde Field (later Mrs. Blinn); tintypes of Mary and William Hyde; and letter and sketch by A.B. Frost to Miss Blinn.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence of William R. Field, Pittstown, New York, and Mary Hyde (Field) of New York; diary of Mary Hyde; letter from James A. Garfield, Ohio, to Mary Maxon Hyde Field, acknowledging her recent letter and recalling his graduation from Williams College; autographed photograph of Garfield (1880); F.W. Field's notes on his family's acquaintance with President Garfield and on the Hyde and Field genealogies; daguerreotype (ca. 1860) of Mrs. William Field holding her infant daughter, Addie Hyde Field (later Mrs. Blinn); tintypes of Mary and William Hyde; and letter and sketch by A.B. Frost to Miss Blinn.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Field family.; Field, Addie Hyde.; Field, Mary Hyde.; Field, William R.; Frost, A. B.; Garfield, James A. (James Abram), 1831-1881.; Hyde family.; Williams College--Students.
Subjects:
Family--New York (State); Women--Diaries.
Form and Genre Terms:
Daguerreotypes.; Diaries.; Genealogies.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Diary of Mary Maxon Hyde, written at Lansingburgh Female Seminary, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters of William Field and Mary Hyde, Feb. 15-May 20, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letters of William Field and Mary Hyde, May 21-July 1, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letters of William Field and Mary Hyde, July 6-Sept. 20, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letters of William Field and Mary Hyde, Sept. 21-Dec. 28, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letters of William Field and Mary Hyde, Jan. 2-May 6, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters of William Field and Mary Hyde, 1860-1861, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letters of William Field and Mary Hyde, 1865, 1873, 1878, 1880-1881 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Newspaper clipping (also, on inside of back cover) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Poems and sketches by Mary Hyde Field (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Lingham - explanation of silver-cased article (see small box in Box 3) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "Splatterdash" by Mary Hyde Field (Box 2, Folder 1)
- "Co-operative Housekeeping" by Mary Hyde Field (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous writings, probably by Mary Hyde Field, 1848, 1868, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous writings (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Sketch - land deeded to Mary Hyde Field, 1868 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- James A. Garfield letter and portrait, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Frederick W. Field - Christmas cards, 1956, 1959, 1961, 1964, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Miscellany (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Cornelliana, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Memorabilia: maps; hickory nut dolls; Solvay medallions; small lantern [?]; "Lingham" (idol in silver case - see Folder 11 in Box 1); World War I service buttons; Erie Canal medallion; daguerreotype of Mary Hyde Field and Addie Hyde Field; tintypes of William Field (1835-1891), ca. 1860, and Mary Field, 1833-1889; Indian arrowheads (Box 3)